

10 Browns Ct. Clavton, Melbourne, Australia

□ (+61) 41-3725464 | Saadkwi12@hotmail.com | Asaadahmad123.github.io | DoweredByME | Casad-ahmad-kwi123

"Be a yardstick of quality."

# Summary.

I am an Electrical Engineer as well as a freelance Software developer. I am interested in Internet of Things, Intelligent Robotics, Artificial Intelligence as well as Web / Mobile / Desktop Application Development. I love to read and attempt to implement new research papers and techniques relevant to my fields of interest. I also like to learn new programming languages, frameworks and methods to make my work more efficient and amazing.

I am currently pursuing Masters of Advanced Engineering (Electrical Engineering) from Monash University, Clayton Campus. I have completed my Bachelor of Electrical Engineering from National University of Sciences and Technology, Pakistan.

## **Education**

**Monash University** 

MASTER OF ADVANCED ENGINEERING - ELECTRICAL ENGINEEERING

Clayton Campus, Australia

Aug 2019 - Present

### National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST)

BACHELOR OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

• CGPA: 3.52/4.00

H-12, Islamabad, Pakistan

Sep. 2015 - May 2019

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### Pak-Arab Oil Refinery Ltd.

**ENGINEERING SERVICES INTERN** 

Punjab, Pakistan

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

· Planning, designing and execution of electrical engineering tasks of the projects being carried out at the oil refinery.

### ABB Power and Automation Ltd.

Lahore, Punjab, Pakistan

SALES & UTILITIES INTERN

Jun. 2017 - Aug. 2017

· Exploring ongoing projects in the country and devising strategies to sell the products and services provided by the company.

### Sugar Mills, Thal Industries

Layyah, Punjab, Pakistan

**ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING INTERN** 

Jun. 2016 - Aug. 2016

· Checking and carrying out proper maintenance of instrumentation in the process area of the sugar mills.

### Ski**lls**\_

**Programming** Python, MATLAB, C/C++, C#, JavaScript, PHP, Node JS

**Libraries** OpenGL, OpenCV, Keras, PyTorch **Electrical Design** Multisim, Proteus, Adobe Eagle

Web Laravel, Redux, ReactJS, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS

**Desktop / Mobile Applications** Electron, Xamarin, React Native, PhoneGap, Iconic

Computer Networking WebRTC, MQTT, Wireshark

Languages English, Urdu

# Projects.

- 1. Brain Computer Interface, User Interface leveraging Steady State Visually Evoked Potential.
- 2. Dance moves extraction from video, Extracting 3D skeleton of dancer using Pose Estimation.
- 3. **Face detection**, Implementation of FaceNet.
- **Tele-operation of Micro Cell Injection System**, using WebRTC and MQTT technology. 4.
- 5. roVBot, WebRTC based, globally tele-operated observation robot using internet.
- glass.h, a simple 2D graphics library in C/C++ based on GLUT.h. 6.

SAAD AHMAD · RÉSUMÉ